{
    "id": "de0aaf7faa3641c6b560222f89b6d404",
    "title": "Types Of Sentences",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "She passed her exam because she had a good teacher.",
            "description": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple",
                "Complex",
                "Compound"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She sat facing me across the table.",
            "description": "A simple sentence has just one clause.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple",
                "Complex",
                "Compound"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He worked hard but he could not pass the exam.",
            "description": "A compound sentence has two or more coordinate clauses introduced by the conjunctions and, but, or, for, so, either..or, neither...nor, both..and, not only...but also. ",
            "answers": [
                "Simple",
                "Complex",
                "Compound"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I am anxious to contact him.",
            "description": "A simple sentence has just one clause.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple",
                "Complex",
                "Compound"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "No one can stop him doing what he wants to.",
            "description": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple",
                "Complex",
                "Compound"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Always check the oil before you start the car.",
            "description": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple",
                "Complex",
                "Compound"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "They considered him a genius.",
            "description": "A simple sentence has just one clause.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple",
                "Complex",
                "Compound"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "At no time was she aware of what was happening.",
            "description": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple",
                "Complex",
                "Compound"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If I am late my father takes me to school.",
            "description": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "Simple",
                "Complex",
                "Compound"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He neither drinks nor smokes.",
            "description": "A compound sentence has two or more coordinate clauses introduced by the conjunctions and, but, or, for, so, either..or, neither...nor, both..and, not only...but also. ",
            "answers": [
                "Simple",
                "Complex",
                "Compound"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He failed the exam and nobody was surprised.",
            "description": "A compound sentence has two or more coordinate clauses introduced by the conjunctions and, but, or, for, so, either..or, neither...nor, both..and, not only...but also. ",
            "answers": [
                "Simple",
                "Complex",
                "Compound"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He was upset but he said nothing.",
            "description": "A compound sentence has two or more coordinate clauses introduced by the conjunctions and, but, or, for, so, either..or, neither...nor, both..and, not only...but also. ",
            "answers": [
                "Simple",
                "Complex",
                "Compound"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}